Guide to the Charles Hill Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Course Materials
  - Intellectual Circles
    - Annan, "The Dons", 1999 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Arabists 17 October 2007 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Berlin salon - Hannah Arendt, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Boswell's Johnson, 1913–2008 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Brotherhood of the bomb, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Charlemagne and his followers, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Church, R. W. "The Oxford Apostles", 1922 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Circles and business, 2008–2009 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Circles (quotes), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Confucius circles, 2008–2009 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - CR/Elizabeth I and her courtiers, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - De Gaulle, "The King and his Court", Undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - DeLord, Richard "The Great Jew Circle", 1988 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Dr. Johnson's club, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Elaine Pagels, "Judas and the Twelve", 2008 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Erasmus and Calasso, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Founders - Mount Vernon, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Founding brothers, 1990–2003 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Frank, Robert "Harvey and the Oxford Physiologists", 1980 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Franklin D. Roosevelt's inner circle, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Frayn, Michael "Copenhagen", 2005 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Freud, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Freud and his disciples, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Freud circle images, Undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Freud images, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Gates, "Need to Upgrade Nuclear Arsenal", 2008 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Gay, Peter, Freud, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Gay, Peter, Freud - embattled founder psychoanalytic politics, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Gibbon decline and fall - Swift, Gibbon, Milton, 2004–2005 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Grosskurth - The Secret Ring (text), Undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Homer - the embassy to Achilles, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Humanities-- Intellectual Circles course and syllabus materials, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Intellectual Circles II, with syllabus, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - John Brown and the Secret Six (C. Vann Woodward), 1952–2003 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - In the Matter of J. Robert Oppenheimer, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - John Brown images, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Kazin, European Writers in Exile (intellectual isolation), 1980 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - King Arthur's roundtable, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Kojéve's Hegelian circle, Paris 1930s, 1991–2009 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Kuhn, Structure of Scientific Revolutions, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Letters from Einstein to Roosevelt, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Lincoln's team of rivals, 2008–2009 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Makari, "Making the Freudians" (text), 1985–2008 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - McNeill Emerson - quote on university on deportment, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Newman's movement, 1990–2008 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - New York poets, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - New York poets, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Oxford conspirators (Newman), 2008 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Paris in the time of Aquinas, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Personal relations at the summit, Britain and Germany 19th century, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Personnel, Undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Picasso and his circle, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Plato, Symposium, 2005–2008 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Plato, Symposium (text), Undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Poe and his circle, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Powell, At Lady Molly's, Undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Raphael's School of Athens, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Robinson, The Secrets of Judas, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Roustang, Dire Mastery (text), Undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Russian thinkers (The Coast of Utopia), 2007 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Saint-Simon at Versailles, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - San Francisco Renaissance (Beats), 1989 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Science and statecraft (Heisenberg and the bomb), 2001–2007 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Paradigms or dialogues? (Kuhn versus Beller), Undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Socrates, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - "Socrates and Freud", Undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Socrates and Freud (text), Undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Supreme Court, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Syllabus - Circles, 2008–2009 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Syllabus and images, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - The Farm, Hall transcript (and photographs), Undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - The Florentine Academy, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - The Kreisan Circle (anti-Hitler plot), 2008 October 31 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - The Last Supper, Undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - The Philby Spy Ring, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - The Salon (War and Peace), 2008 November (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - The Secret Ring: Freud's Inner Circle, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - The Secret Six and John Brown (text and notes), Undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - The Twelve Apostles, Undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Tinker: The Salon and English Letters, 1915 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Werner Heisenberg on the Nazi Revolution James C. O'Flaherty, Undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - West, "The Death of Wolfe", 2005–2008 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - What Did Heisenberg Tell Bohr about the Bomb? Jeremy Bernstein, Scientific American, 1995 May (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - What Happened at Vatican II?, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Wienerskreis in America, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Wittgenstein, Undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Wittgenstein and the Vienna Circle, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Wright, The Fellowship, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - International Ideas and Institutions
    - Course reader (partial), 1996–2004 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Course readers, 1776–2004 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Course readings, 1776–2004 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Notes and reading materials, 2002–2004 (Box 15, Folder 16-17)
  - Literature of Statecraft
    - 1919 Versailles (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - A Note on the Tone of Greek Diplomacy, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - The Ancient Art of Statecraft, 1946–2005 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Arendt on America (foundry, Constitution, government, compact), Undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Art after the Paris Commune, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Ashley, Louis XIV and the Greatness of France, 1965–1981 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Auden, New Year Letter (diplomatic stana), 1941 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Auden, New Year Letter, 1940–2003 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Augustine (and F. Scott Fitzgerald), 2000 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - The balcony in Henry James - first paragraph of Ambassadors, 1969–2004 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Basic documents (syllabi, exams), 2004 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Benet: John Brown's Body, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Benjamin Franklin (statue) (Indian treaties), Undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Benjamin Franklin, Indian treaties, 1942–2004 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Berlin Diary, William Shirer, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Bismark, the Ems dispatch as dramatist, 1961–2002 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Blenheim, 1986–2003 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Byron/Chevening/Sanian/Alcmerdae, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Chaucer: The Diplomat, Undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Classical speeches, Undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Code of Peace: Ethics and Security in the World of the Warlord States by Doroth V. Jones (the Danzig case), 1989–1994 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - The Coming of the Third Reich, New York Times review, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Confucius "Thread' (4.15), 1990–2004 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Coriolanus (Shakespeare), 2004 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Course reader, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Dante and cosmology (3-sphere), Mark Peterson in American Journal of Physics, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - The Diplomats, 1919-1939 edited by Craig and Gilbert, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Dorothy Thompson and the Nazi rise, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Dostoevsky, Demons, Undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Dreams and Delusions, chapter 5 Fritz Stein, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Elizabeth I, 1994–2004 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Emerson and Thoreau, Grand Strategy, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - The Elizabethan Age, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Ems (Franco-Prussian) originals, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Ems/Franco-Prussian War/Paris Commune, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Findley,Famous Last Words; Namier, Diplomatic Prelude 1938-1939; Shirer,Rise and Fall of the Third Reich, 1960–1981 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - First packet, Undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Francs Bacon, "Of Negotiating", undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - George Bush (1796-1859) Life of Mohammed, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - George F. Kennan, The Long Telegram, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - German Offensive, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Grand Strategic Extravaganza focused on the Pacific Northwest (manifest destiny), 2003 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Grand Strategy Philip II (Felipe Secundo), 1992–2002 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Hamilton/Washington To the Farewell Address ("the prose of American statecraft"), Undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Heidegger, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Henry Adams' diplomatic education, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Henry Adams volume I: VI, XIV-XVII, History of the United States during the Administration of Thomas Jefferson - Selections, 1889 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Henry James, The Ambassadors, 1969–2004 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Hermann Georing: The Man and His Works by Erich Gritzback (selections), 1938 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Herodotus lecture, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Holbein, The Ambassadors, Undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Illustrations, 1971–1980 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Indians, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Introduction, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Ivanhoe's and Odysseus's return, 2000–2004 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Journals of Lewis and Clark (selections), 1804 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Kennan, From Prague after Munich (no asylum for Jews), 1968 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Kissinger and the diplomatic memoir, 2003–2004 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Kissinger: diplomatic memoirs as literature, 1979–1990 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Klemperer, I Will Bear Witness, 1933, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Lewis and Clark, peace pipes and diplomacy, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Literature of statecraft, 1991–2000 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Livy and the rise of Rome/virtues, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Louis XIV and Versailles, Undated (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Louis XIV, force, order, diplomacy, 2003–2006 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Louisiana Purchase, 1998–2004 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Manet, A Bar at the Foiles Bergere, Undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Manifest destiny Federalist 1 and 9, 10, 1787 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Marat, Death of..French Revolution, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Machiavelli, Art of War, Undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Marvell, "An Horatian Ode", 1970–2003 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Marx -The Paris Commune, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Memoir package - Kissinger, Shultz, Boutros-Ghali, 1982–1999 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Merrill, "In the Hall of Mirrors" 1959 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Mistress Masham's Repose, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Nazi rise (extra handouts), 1978–2003 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Nicolson: Diplomacy is Protean, 1919 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Notes and published materials, 1997–2002 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Odyssey, 1995–2001 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Ozymandias, Percy Byshe Shelley, 2003–2005 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Pepys, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Personal memoirs of P. H. Sheridan, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Pottier and Degeyter - The Internationale, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - The recognition of Israel, 1967–2005 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Rimbaud and the commune, 1966–2004 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Robinson Crusoe (and Rousseau), 2005 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Saint-Simon at Versailles, 2001–2004 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - The sounds history makes, 2003–2005 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Spring 2004 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Swift, Jonathan (1667-1745), 1985–2004 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Syllabus, 2001–2004 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Tacitus, Undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - T. H. White, The Once and Future King, 1974–1988 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Thomas Wolfe, "I Have a Thing to Tell You" You Can't Go Home Again, 1962–2003 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Thoreau,A Week(version of Izaak Walton), 2005 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Thucydides, Debate at Sparta, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - T. S. Eliot, The Waste Land and modernism's breaking of forms, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Two "Mahomets" (Gibson and Irving), Undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Walton, The Compleate Angler, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Washington Irving Mahomet, Undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Versailles and the United States, 1986–1990 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Vietnam Anloc, Undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Virgil, Aeneid, Undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Woolf Orlando (Elizabeth), 1990 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - War of 1812, Undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Washburne chapters 2, 7, Recollections of a Minister to France, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - William Dodd and Martha Dodd,Through Embassy Eyes, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Wilson and the 14 Points, 1974–2004 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Wilson at Versailles 1919, 2000–2004 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Woodrow Wilson (The House on "S" Street), 1992 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Xenophon, Anabasis, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Metahistories
    - America, 2014 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Augustine (and Confucius versus Taipings), Undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Bibliography, 2014 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Christendom Augustine - Dante, 2014 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Civitas: Augustus, Virgil, Ovid, 2003–2004 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Clio Kant and Hegel (history replaces theology), 2014 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Collingwood, 2004–2005 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Cosmos: Zeus's Plan, Iliad, the Axial Age, 2003–2014 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Counter-civilization (Rousseau, Marx, Ur-Germans, Nietzsche, Freud), 2014 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Course readings for HUMS 303: Metahistory, 2014 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Dialectic of Enlightenment, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Grand Strategy, Spengler, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Hegel, Undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Hegel (see also Grand Strategy, End of History), 2004 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Horkheimer (Habermaron), Undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Horkheimer, Max, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Introduction to "Metahistories" (HUMS 303), 2014 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - IS Science, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - IS Toynbee Volkerwanderung Intelligible Field of Study, 1995–2015 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Islam and metahistory, 2010–2012 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Joachim, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Joachim of Fiore, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Karl Popper and "Historicism", 2007 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Kurt Gödel - "The God of the Mathematicians", 2010 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Literature (Mimesis) Charles Hill on Literary Criticism, 2000–2014 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Metahistory: Marx, 1950–2000 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Metahistory, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Metahistory, the metahistorical tradition, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Metahistories, 2014 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Mid-term, 2014 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Notes and published materials, 2002–2014 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Notes, 2005–2014 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Nietzsche and freedom (3 key moments), 2012 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Science, 1998–2014 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Secular age? - end of the "modern"?, 2014 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Spengler, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Syllabus and notes, 2014 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Toynbee, 1961–2004 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Notes for teaching Grand Strategy courses
    - American Intellectual History: the stages, 2016 October 17 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Aristotle/Vitoria/American Indians, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Articles on books and authors, 1942–2007 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Battle of Midway, Undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Baylor: Ten-Year Plan, Charles Hill proposal, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Benjamin Franklin, Undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Bureaucracy (Grand Strategy), 2010 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Career talk, "Why Smart People Fail" and what is Grand Strategy? Learn-able?, 2008 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Chart: international-global affairs at Yale, 2014 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Church and state, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Churchill, 2003-2012 (Box 23, Folder 11-12)
    - Clausewitz and Hegel and Napoleon, 2005–2007 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Confucius, 1990–2004 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - C. P. Snow, Science and Government, 2009 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Daniel Webster (Emerson, Benet, Stein), Undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Diplomats (individuals), 1991 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Directed Studies - Rome (Livy, Cicero), 2008 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Emily Dickinson, Undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Extravaganza--Grand Strategy (International Studies - America), 2003 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Fukuyama, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Globalization and trade (Solman exercse), 2001–2004 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Grand Strategy - Authoritarian politics, 2012 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Grand Strategy - Big thinks (Ikenberry, Kupchan, Nye, Nau, Mead), 2002 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Grand Strategy - Causes, 2004–2008 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Grand Strategy - Clausewitz, 2005–2009 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Grand Strategy - Consequences, 2006–2007 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Grand Strategy - De Gaulle, 2008 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Grand Strategy - Doric and Ionic, 2009 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Grand Strategy - Economy and finance logic chain, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Grand Strategy - Elizabethan statecraft, Undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Grand Strategy - Ethics/Morality and the International (special session), 2005 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Grand Strategy - Founders, 2007–2011 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Grand Strategy - Fukuyama and Huntington, 2005 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Grand Strategy - For alumni, 2012–2013 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Grand Strategy - Ghandi (non-violent movements), 0199–2011 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Grand Strategy - Globalization, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Grand Strategy - Grand Strategy as civilization, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Grand Strategy - Images (Theodore Roosevelt and White Fleet, USS Missouri, Don Quixote), Undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Grand Strategy - International financial crisis reborn, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Grand Strategy - Kant and the internationalist project, and Metternich, 2000–2009 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Grand Strategy - Key articles/cartoons, 2002–2006 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Grand Strategy - Leadership - virtue/manliness, Undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Grand Strategy - Machiavelli, 2012 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Grand Strategy - Marx, Lenin, Stalin, Mao (authoritarianism including Germany and Japan), 2000–2009 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Grand Strategy - Morality and Grand Strategy (special session), 2003 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Grand Strategy - Notes for first fall sessions, 2007 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Grand Strategy - Odysseus - Argonauts - Dante (long version of Charles Hill's toast at Grand Strategy party), 2007 March (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Grand Strategy - Of Lord of the Rings, 2007 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Grand Strategy - Optimism and Pessimism, 2008–2015 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Grand Strategy - On writing, 2000–2008 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Grand Strategy - Pierce: Abduction, 2009 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Grand Strategy - Reagan - Gorbachev, 2000–2012 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Grand Strategy - Religion, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Grand Strategy - Thucydides, 2007–2015 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Horace handout, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Horace (lecture), 2007 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Images used for classes, Undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Imperial geopolitics, 2007–2013 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Imperial geopolitics (images), Undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Imperial politics (and the United States empire), 2009–2012 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Kant, constitutinalism, and the Federalist Papers, 2015 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Kennan (and Kissinger), 2006–2007 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - "Las Casas", Undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Laocoon and the Trojan horse, 2009–2012 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Latin America, 2002 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Mackinder, 2003–2005 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Maraghi's letter to Wingate, 1915–2003 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - McKinley to Marx, 2006–2007 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Mearsheimer: "offensive realism", 2002 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous grand strategy materials, 2014–2016 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Middle East (Olivier Roy), 2008 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Notetaking, 1997–2010 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Notecards for grand strategy simulations, 2013–2014 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Panama, 1999–2004 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Philip II and Elizabeth, 2002–2016 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Philip II and Elizabeth (images), 2006–2009 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Post-Cold War grand strategy, 1999–2011 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Queen Elizabeth I's title (latin) and answer on marriage (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Religion, 1994–2003 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Religion: Notes (RIS/GS/IS), 2002 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Religion and 'The International", 1989–2002 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Return of Big Power Rivalry? (authoritarian-capitalist model), 2008 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Rome images, 2000–2002 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Salisbury (and Paul Kennedy), 1962–2010 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Scipio Africanus, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Sun Tzu, 2004–2009 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Sun Tzu (handouts), 2001–2013 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - The End of History Hegel-Kojeve-Beckett, 1997–2002 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Theodore Roosevelt, Woodrow Wilson, and Franklin D. Roosevelt, 2006–2008 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - What is Grand Strategy? (students), 2008 December 8 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - What is Grand Strategy? chart, literature, and list of books, 2010 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - World Fellows/GS Thucydides and Kant, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Yale-National University of Singapore course (Penelope) Singapore, 2013 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Zeitgeist Watch, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Oratory in Statecraft
    - Abba Eban, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Abraham Lincoln (Gettysburg, second inaugural addresses), circa 2002 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Adam Smith, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Adlai Stevenson acceptance speech, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Arabic rhetoric (and how Bin Laden betrays it), 2004 October (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Attic orators on war and peace, circa 1990 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Benjamin Franklin, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - The Brothers Karamazov, circa 2002 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Burke-Impeachment revolution, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Burke, Kenneth- a grammar of motives (four tropes), 1969 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Bush inaugral address, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Caesarian orations with markings, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - The church's way of speaking, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Churchill, "The Scaffolding of Rhetoric" (1897), circa 2000s (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Cicero-Caesarian speeches, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence and clippings on oratory, 2016 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Cicero-de oratore, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Course schedule and readings, circa 2013 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Draft of syllabus and course reader, undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - De Las Casas-debates at Valladolid, undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Democracy and rhetoric-Fontana, Nederman, Remer, undated (Box 28, Folder 21)